<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<conferenceItinerary xmlns="http://pereztextileconservation.com/schema/travel"
                     attendee="Jesse Perez"
                     event="AIC Annual Meeting 2026"
                     location="Salt Lake City, Utah"
                     created="2026-02-12">

  <personalInfo>
    <name>Jesse Perez</name>
    <affiliation>Perez Textile Conservation, Jamaica Plain, MA</affiliation>
    <phone>(617) 555-3800</phone>
    <email>jesse.perez@Finthesiss.ai</email>
    <emergencyContact name="Maria Delgado" phone="(860) 555-3802" relationship="sister"/>
  </personalInfo>

  <travel>
    <outbound>
      <departure date="2026-11-10" time="07:45" airport="BOS" terminal="B"/>
      <arrival date="2026-11-10" time="11:20" airport="SLC"/>
      <confirmationRef>AIR-BOS-SLC-1110</confirmationRef>
      <notes>Morning flight. Laptop carry-on only. USB-C adapter for presentation room.</notes>
    </outbound>
    <return>
      <departure date="2026-11-14" time="16:30" airport="SLC"/>
      <arrival date="2026-11-14" time="22:05" airport="BOS" terminal="B"/>
      <confirmationRef>AIR-SLC-BOS-1114</confirmationRef>
      <notes>Return same day as birthday. Pick up cafe de olla supplies in Fenwick on the way.</notes>
    </return>
  </travel>

  <lodging>
    <hotel name="Downtown Salt Lake City hotel, booked via short-term rental" checkIn="2026-11-10" checkOut="2026-11-14"/>
    <confirmationRef>STAY-SLC-2026-1110</confirmationRef>
    <notes>King room, quiet floor requested. Coffee maker essential. Within walking distance of conference venue.</notes>
  </lodging>

  <schedule>

    <day date="2026-11-10" label="Arrival Day">
      <item time="11:30" type="arrival">Land SLC, collect bag, transit to hotel.</item>
      <item time="13:00" type="meal">Late lunch near hotel, decompress from travel.</item>
      <item time="15:00" type="task">Conference registration and badge pickup at convention center.</item>
      <item time="16:00" type="task">Walk presentation room, confirm AV setup, test slide deck from USB.</item>
      <item time="17:30" type="meeting">Pre-conference reception for textile specialty group. Connect with Priya Nair, who arrives same afternoon.</item>
      <item time="19:30" type="meal">Dinner with Priya. Confirm mutual referral and upcoming conference paper topics.</item>
    </day>

    <day date="2026-11-11" label="Day One">
      <item time="08:00" type="session">Opening plenary, full auditorium.</item>
      <item time="10:00" type="session">Session: Preventive Conservation in Institutional Collections. Note-taking for Peabody Essex sampler storage upgrade proposal.</item>
      <item time="12:30" type="meal">Lunch break. Touch base with Elena Vasquez (MFA) if she is attending remotely or in person.</item>
      <item time="14:00" type="session">Session: New Approaches in Textile Mounting and Framing. Attend fully - directly related to Thursday presentation.</item>
      <item time="16:00" type="session">Poster session. Walk posters, identify any colleagues working on Latin American or Ottoman textile research.</item>
      <item time="18:00" type="social">Informal gathering with graduate student mentees and recent Winterthur cohort.</item>
    </day>

    <day date="2026-11-12" label="Day Two">
      <item time="08:30" type="session">Session: Ethics of Conservation Intervention. Core professional interest - full attendance.</item>
      <item time="10:30" type="personal">Final review of presentation slides. Quiet room or lobby corner. No distractions.</item>
      <item time="12:00" type="meal">Lunch with Priya and one other colleague from the New York conservation community.</item>
      <item time="14:00" type="presentation">PRESENTING: "Reversible Mounting Techniques for Historic Textiles: A Practical Framework." Room TBD. Approximately 35 minutes including questions.</item>
      <item time="15:30" type="social">Post-presentation corridor conversation - field colleagues, questions, card exchange.</item>
      <item time="17:00" type="session">Optional: Late-day lightning talks if energy permits.</item>
      <item time="19:00" type="meal">Conference dinner with specialty group. Budget dinner, receipts for tax records.</item>
    </day>

    <day date="2026-11-13" label="Day Three">
      <item time="09:00" type="session">Session: Latin American Heritage Textiles - Documentation and Access. Attend fully.</item>
      <item time="11:00" type="task">Visit exhibitor floor. Suppliers with specialty materials: check new product lines. Compare pricing for crepeline alternatives. Do not commit to any purchase over $300 without reviewing studio budget first.</item>
      <item time="13:00" type="meal">Solo lunch. Decompression time. Notebook for any observations from the week.</item>
      <item time="14:30" type="session">Workshop: Dye Identification for Field Conservators. Optional attendance based on energy levels.</item>
      <item time="17:00" type="social">Closing reception. Brief appearance. Check out by 18:30.</item>
      <item time="20:00" type="personal">Early evening walk in Salt Lake City, rest. Call Carmen to confirm November 1 visit logistics.</item>
    </day>

    <day date="2026-11-14" label="Departure - Birthday">
      <item time="07:00" type="personal">Birthday. No morning commitments scheduled. Walk if hotel location allows.</item>
      <item time="09:00" type="task">Check out of hotel. Confirm bag stored until departure.</item>
      <item time="11:00" type="optional">Optional: morning session if flight allows sufficient buffer.</item>
      <item time="13:30" type="travel">Depart hotel for airport. Allow 2.5 hours before departure.</item>
      <item time="16:30" type="travel">Flight SLC to BOS.</item>
    </day>

  </schedule>

  <budget>
    <category name="Airfare" estimated="420.00" currency="USD"/>
    <category name="Lodging (4 nights)" estimated="680.00" currency="USD"/>
    <category name="Meals (per diem x 5 days)" estimated="275.00" currency="USD"/>
    <category name="Registration" estimated="310.00" currency="USD"/>
    <category name="Ground transport" estimated="80.00" currency="USD"/>
    <category name="Incidentals" estimated="60.00" currency="USD"/>
    <total estimated="1825.00" currency="USD"/>
    <notes>Full trip cost below $300 threshold per line item (except registration). Total approved by Jesse as part of annual conference allocation. Receipts retained for Schedule C deduction.</notes>
  </budget>

  <tasks>
    <task id="T1" status="complete">Register for conference and submit abstract</task>
    <task id="T2" status="complete">Submit paper abstract - accepted February 2026</task>
    <task id="T3" status="complete">Book flights</task>
    <task id="T4" status="in-progress">Finalize and rehearse presentation deck</task>
    <task id="T5" status="pending">Coordinate studio coverage with Samuel for November 11 to 14</task>
    <task id="T6" status="pending">Print poster if required by session chair</task>
    <task id="T7" status="pending">Pack: laptop, USB-C adapter, printed slide backup, notebook, business cards, hand brace for travel</task>
  </tasks>

</conferenceItinerary>
