<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<restorationProject>
  <owner>Andrew Roberts</owner>
  <workshop>Garage workbench, 1528 Heatherton Lane, Naperville, IL</workshop>
  <tool>
    <type>No. 4 bench smoothing plane</type>
    <acquired date="2026-01-24" source="Antique mall, stall 41" price="22.50" currency="USD" />
    <estimatedManufacture>1910 to 1918</estimatedManufacture>
    <identification>Type 11 by the feature checklist: low knob, three patent dates behind the frog, raised logo on the iron.</identification>
    <remark>Older than my father was. It will be treated accordingly.</remark>
  </tool>
  <conditionAtIntake>
    <item part="Body and sole">Uniform light rust across sole and cheeks, heavier pitting at the toe, no cracks in the casting. Rings true tapped end to end.</item>
    <item part="Japanning">Roughly 60 percent intact. Acceptable for a working restoration, not a museum piece.</item>
    <item part="Iron">Honest length left, about 60 percent. Chipbreaker mates poorly, daylight at the corners.</item>
    <item part="Lever cap">Fine under the grime.</item>
    <item part="Tote and knob">Tote cracked at the base through the lower screw hole. Knob sound. Both rosewood, both worth saving.</item>
  </conditionAtIntake>
  <workLog>
    <entry date="2026-01-25">Full teardown, parts tray photographed and labeled. Soaked all steel hardware in rust remover for 24 hours. Body and frog cleaned by hand; chose against electrolysis, the pitting does not justify the setup.</entry>
    <entry date="2026-01-27">Sole lapping on float glass, adhesive backed 80 grit then 120, 180, 220. Started 0.006 inch hollow at the mouth, finished within 0.0015 inch over the length. Flat where it matters at toe, mouth, and heel.</entry>
    <entry date="2026-01-28">Frog seat dressed lightly with a fine file, full contact restored. Frog face lapped flat to 220.</entry>
    <entry date="2026-02-01">Tote repaired, cleaned the crack with acetone, glued with slow set epoxy, clamped overnight, redrilled the screw seat. Both rosewood pieces refinished with boiled linseed oil, three coats.</entry>
    <entry date="2026-02-10">Iron flattened on the back to a polish at the working inch. Primary bevel reground to 25 degrees on the slow wheel, honed at 30 with a secondary bevel. Chipbreaker mating edge dressed until no daylight, set at one thirty second from the edge.</entry>
    <entry date="2026-02-12">Reassembly and tuning. Mouth set fine, lateral centered. Took shavings off scrap walnut at just under 0.002 inch, full width, no tearout. The sound is right: a clean hiss, no chatter.</entry>
  </workLog>
  <measurements>
    <measurement name="Sole flatness at intake" value="0.006 inch hollow" />
    <measurement name="Sole flatness after lapping" value="0.0015 inch over length" />
    <measurement name="Primary bevel" value="25 degrees" />
    <measurement name="Honing angle" value="30 degrees" />
    <measurement name="Finish shaving thickness" value="just under 0.002 inch" />
  </measurements>
  <remaining>
    <task>Touch up japanning losses with engine enamel, masked, two thin coats. Cosmetic only, the tool already works.</task>
    <task>Decide whether it stays at this bench or goes to Sam's workbench in waiting fund.</task>
  </remaining>
  <summary>
    <hoursToDate>9.5</hoursToDate>
    <consumablesCost currency="USD">0.00</consumablesCost>
    <verdict>They do not make them like this anymore, and they barely made them like this then.</verdict>
  </summary>
</restorationProject>
