<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<courseRecord>
  <course>
    <title>Writing Your Life: The Personal Essay</title>
    <provider>Naperville Public Library, Nichols Library</provider>
    <location>Community Room B</location>
    <format>Six Wednesday evenings, 6:30 to 8:30 PM</format>
    <dates start="2025-10-01" end="2025-11-05" />
    <instructor>Diane Keller</instructor>
    <cost>Free with library card, registration required, limited to 14</cost>
    <participant>Andrew Roberts</participant>
    <status>Completed</status>
  </course>
  <about>For adults who have a life worth writing about, which the instructor wishes to note is all of them. No writing experience required. Each week pairs a short craft discussion with writing time and gentle, structured feedback. The aim is one finished personal essay by the end of the session.</about>
  <schedule>
    <week number="1" date="2025-10-01">
      <topic>What makes an essay personal</topic>
      <assignment>A list of ten true things you could write about and one you think you cannot.</assignment>
    </week>
    <week number="2" date="2025-10-08">
      <topic>Beginnings. Finding the doorway into the material.</topic>
      <assignment>Three opening paragraphs for three different essays.</assignment>
    </week>
    <week number="3" date="2025-10-15">
      <topic>Scene and detail. The concrete noun is your friend.</topic>
      <assignment>One scene, 500 words, no abstractions.</assignment>
    </week>
    <week number="4" date="2025-10-22">
      <topic>The hard subjects. Writing about loss and the people we love without sentimentality and without armor.</topic>
      <assignment>Begin your full draft.</assignment>
    </week>
    <week number="5" date="2025-10-29">
      <topic>Workshop night. Half the class reads drafts aloud for structured response.</topic>
      <assignment>Revise.</assignment>
    </week>
    <week number="6" date="2025-11-05">
      <topic>Workshop night, remaining readers, and endings. What an essay owes the reader at the door.</topic>
      <assignment>Final drafts due by email within one week for written comments.</assignment>
    </week>
  </schedule>
  <groundRules>
    <rule>What is read in this room stays in this room.</rule>
    <rule>Feedback names what is working before what is not, and is always about the writing, never the life.</rule>
    <rule>You may pass on reading aloud at any time, once.</rule>
  </groundRules>
  <personalNote>Left me privately thrilled and privately mortified. Signed up for whatever they offer in the spring.</personalNote>
</courseRecord>
