<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<operationsManual shop="Sharp Line Cuts" version="3" effective="2026-01-15">
  <section id="opening" title="Opening Procedures">
    <responsibility>Whoever is opening. Arrive by 8:30 AM.</responsibility>
    <step order="1">Unlock front and back doors.</step>
    <step order="2">Turn on lights and HVAC.</step>
    <step order="3">Start the hot lather machine.</step>
    <step order="4">Wipe down all stations, mirrors, and chairs.</step>
    <step order="5">Sweep the floor.</step>
    <step order="6">Check station supply levels: blades, neck strips, disinfectant, capes, towels.</step>
    <step order="7">Boot the point-of-sale tablet and verify the internet connection.</step>
    <step order="8">Start the shop playlist for the day.</step>
    <step order="9">Unlock the front door at 9:00 AM sharp.</step>
  </section>
  <section id="closing" title="Closing Procedures">
    <step order="1">Last client finished by 6:45 PM weekdays, 1:45 PM Sundays.</step>
    <step order="2">Sweep and mop all floors.</step>
    <step order="3">Wipe down all stations and mirrors.</step>
    <step order="4">Clean and oil all clippers.</step>
    <step order="5">Empty and refill the disinfectant jars for the next day.</step>
    <step order="6">Take out the trash.</step>
    <step order="7">Run the point-of-sale end-of-day report and confirm totals.</step>
    <step order="8">Lock the retail product display case.</step>
    <step order="9">Turn off HVAC, lights, and the hot lather machine.</step>
    <step order="10">Lock the back door, then the front door.</step>
    <step order="11">Set the alarm system before leaving.</step>
  </section>
  <section id="sanitation" title="Sanitation Standards">
    <rule>Disinfect every tool that touches a client between each client.</rule>
    <rule>Fresh neck strip and a clean cape for every person in the chair.</rule>
    <rule>Disinfectant jars refreshed daily, never reused across days.</rule>
    <rule>Floors swept between clients during busy stretches, not just at close.</rule>
    <complianceNote>Michigan licensing requires it, clients expect it, and it reflects who we are.</complianceNote>
  </section>
  <section id="maintenance" title="Equipment Maintenance Log Rules">
    <rule>Log clipper blade sharpening or replacement on the maintenance board.</rule>
    <rule>One card per open issue: chair upholstery, plumbing, signage, until done.</rule>
    <reorderPolicy>Reorder station consumables when stock hits the reorder point. James places supplier orders himself.</reorderPolicy>
  </section>
  <section id="client" title="Client Standards">
    <rule>Greet every person who walks in, even mid-cut.</rule>
    <rule>Offer water or coffee to anyone waiting.</rule>
    <rule>If a barber is running behind, give an honest wait time. Do not guess low.</rule>
    <rule>No phones during a cut unless it is an emergency.</rule>
    <rule>Treat every client like a returning client.</rule>
  </section>
</operationsManual>
