<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ProductBacklog version="3.1" product="Analytics Dashboard" lastUpdated="2026-11-15" owner="Stephanie Wells" team="Growth and Analytics Pod">

  <ProductInfo>
    <ProductName>Analytics Dashboard</ProductName>
    <ProductManager>Stephanie Wells</ProductManager>
    <EngineeringLead>Megan Shaw</EngineeringLead>
    <Designer>Tomoko Hayashi</Designer>
    <DataScientist>Ryan Iyer</DataScientist>
    <Engineers>Alex Park, Dana Cruz, Priya Nair, James Okafor</Engineers>
    <FeatureFreeze>2026-10-09</FeatureFreeze>
    <GeneralAvailability>2026-11-13</GeneralAvailability>
    <Status>GA - Hypercare complete November 27, 2026</Status>
  </ProductInfo>

  <ShippedFeatures>

    <Feature id="NS-F001" sprint="S12" status="shipped" shippedDate="2026-10-02">
      <Name>Export to CSV</Name>
      <Description>Users may export any current dashboard view to a CSV file. Export captures the full visible dataset including applied filters, date range, and cohort selection. Rate-limited to 10 exports per hour per account. File size cap 50 MB. Download link expires in 24 hours.</Description>
      <PilotDriving>ENT-PC-001, ENT-PC-002</PilotDriving>
      <AcceptanceCriteria>
        <Criterion>100k-row export completes in under 90 seconds at P95</Criterion>
        <Criterion>Export preserves all applied filters and date range selection</Criterion>
        <Criterion>Download link is secure and expires after 24 hours</Criterion>
        <Criterion>Rate limit error message is clear and actionable</Criterion>
      </AcceptanceCriteria>
      <TestCoverage>92%</TestCoverage>
      <PilotFeedback>ENT-PC-001 Kate Ellison: critical feature, unblocked weekly reporting workflow</PilotFeedback>
      <RICEScore>
        <Reach>320</Reach>
        <Impact>3</Impact>
        <Confidence>90</Confidence>
        <Effort>2</Effort>
        <Total>432</Total>
      </RICEScore>
    </Feature>

    <Feature id="NS-F002" sprint="S12" status="shipped" shippedDate="2026-10-02">
      <Name>Custom date range filter</Name>
      <Description>Users may select any custom date range for dashboard views rather than being limited to preset windows (last 7, 30, 90 days). Calendar picker UI with comparison period option. Saved date ranges persist per user.</Description>
      <PilotDriving>ENT-PC-003</PilotDriving>
      <AcceptanceCriteria>
        <Criterion>Date picker renders correctly on all supported browsers</Criterion>
        <Criterion>Saved ranges persist across sessions</Criterion>
        <Criterion>Comparison period overlay is optional and dismissible</Criterion>
      </AcceptanceCriteria>
      <TestCoverage>88%</TestCoverage>
      <PilotFeedback>ENT-PC-003 Priya Shankar: enables quarter-over-quarter analysis without manual workaround</PilotFeedback>
      <RICEScore>
        <Reach>280</Reach>
        <Impact>2</Impact>
        <Confidence>95</Confidence>
        <Effort>1</Effort>
        <Total>532</Total>
      </RICEScore>
    </Feature>

    <Feature id="NS-F005" sprint="S12" status="shipped" shippedDate="2026-10-02">
      <Name>User-level drill-down</Name>
      <Description>From any cohort view, users can drill down to see individual user activity. Shows event timeline, session frequency, and retention stage for a selected user. Obfuscated by default, with opt-in disclosure per enterprise account settings.</Description>
      <PilotDriving>ENT-PC-002</PilotDriving>
      <AcceptanceCriteria>
        <Criterion>Drill-down from cohort table renders in under 2 seconds at P95</Criterion>
        <Criterion>Default obfuscation applied unless enterprise account explicitly opts in</Criterion>
        <Criterion>User lookup returns results within 500ms</Criterion>
      </AcceptanceCriteria>
      <TestCoverage>90%</TestCoverage>
      <PilotFeedback>ENT-PC-002 Marcus Webb: unlocked investigation of the high-retention cohort we could not explain before</PilotFeedback>
      <RICEScore>
        <Reach>180</Reach>
        <Impact>3</Impact>
        <Confidence>85</Confidence>
        <Effort>3</Effort>
        <Total>153</Total>
      </RICEScore>
    </Feature>

    <Feature id="NS-F003" sprint="S13" status="shipped" shippedDate="2026-10-23">
      <Name>Shared dashboard links</Name>
      <Description>Users can generate a shareable link to any dashboard view. Links preserve filters, date range, and cohort selection. Links can be scoped to view-only or full-account access. Link expiry is configurable (24h, 7d, 30d, permanent).</Description>
      <PilotDriving>ENT-PC-001</PilotDriving>
      <AcceptanceCriteria>
        <Criterion>Shared link renders the exact view state it was created from</Criterion>
        <Criterion>Access control enforced on link type selection</Criterion>
        <Criterion>Permanent links can be revoked by the creating user</Criterion>
      </AcceptanceCriteria>
      <TestCoverage>85%</TestCoverage>
      <PilotFeedback>ENT-PC-001: weekly reporting workflow now fully in-product instead of screenshot email chains</PilotFeedback>
      <RICEScore>
        <Reach>300</Reach>
        <Impact>2</Impact>
        <Confidence>90</Confidence>
        <Effort>2</Effort>
        <Total>270</Total>
      </RICEScore>
    </Feature>

    <Feature id="NS-F006" sprint="S13" status="shipped" shippedDate="2026-10-23">
      <Name>Funnel visualization</Name>
      <Description>Users can build conversion funnels from any sequence of product events. Funnel displays step-by-step conversion rates, drop-off points, and median time between steps. Up to 8 steps per funnel. Funnels can be saved and shared.</Description>
      <PilotDriving>All three pilots</PilotDriving>
      <AcceptanceCriteria>
        <Criterion>Funnel renders in under 3 seconds for datasets with up to 500k events</Criterion>
        <Criterion>Drop-off percentages are mathematically accurate to 2 decimal places</Criterion>
        <Criterion>Median time between steps is calculated correctly</Criterion>
      </AcceptanceCriteria>
      <TestCoverage>87%</TestCoverage>
      <PilotFeedback>All three pilot accounts named funnel visualization in NPS comments as a top-3 feature</PilotFeedback>
      <RICEScore>
        <Reach>350</Reach>
        <Impact>3</Impact>
        <Confidence>90</Confidence>
        <Effort>4</Effort>
        <Total>236</Total>
      </RICEScore>
    </Feature>

    <Feature id="NS-F004" sprint="S14" status="shipped" shippedDate="2026-11-11">
      <Name>Email digest reports</Name>
      <Description>Users can schedule automated email digests with key dashboard metrics. Configurable frequency (daily, weekly, monthly). Digest includes sparkline charts, key metric delta, and a direct link to the dashboard. Supports up to 5 recipients per digest.</Description>
      <PilotDriving>ENT-PC-001</PilotDriving>
      <AcceptanceCriteria>
        <Criterion>Emails deliver within 5 minutes of scheduled time at P95</Criterion>
        <Criterion>Sparkline charts render correctly in Gmail and Outlook</Criterion>
        <Criterion>Unsubscribe link functional within 2 clicks</Criterion>
        <Criterion>No duplicate sends on retry</Criterion>
      </AcceptanceCriteria>
      <TestCoverage>84%</TestCoverage>
      <PilotFeedback>ENT-PC-001: allows sharing insights with non-platform stakeholders</PilotFeedback>
      <RICEScore>
        <Reach>200</Reach>
        <Impact>2</Impact>
        <Confidence>80</Confidence>
        <Effort>3</Effort>
        <Total>107</Total>
      </RICEScore>
    </Feature>

    <Feature id="NS-F010" sprint="S14" status="shipped" shippedDate="2026-11-11">
      <Name>Messaging alert integration</Name>
      <Description>Users can configure threshold-based alerts that post to a team messaging channel when a key metric crosses a defined threshold. Supports absolute and percentage-change triggers. Alert payload includes metric name, current value, threshold, and dashboard link.</Description>
      <PilotDriving>ENT-PC-002</PilotDriving>
      <AcceptanceCriteria>
        <Criterion>Alert fires within 5 minutes of threshold crossing at P95</Criterion>
        <Criterion>No duplicate alerts within a 10-minute window for the same threshold</Criterion>
        <Criterion>Webhook isolated in a separate microservice to protect main analytics service</Criterion>
      </AcceptanceCriteria>
      <TestCoverage>82%</TestCoverage>
      <PilotFeedback>ENT-PC-002: real-time alerting replaces manual daily dashboard checks for on-call team</PilotFeedback>
      <RICEScore>
        <Reach>220</Reach>
        <Impact>2</Impact>
        <Confidence>85</Confidence>
        <Effort>2</Effort>
        <Total>187</Total>
      </RICEScore>
    </Feature>

    <Feature id="NS-F007" sprint="S14" status="shipped" shippedDate="2026-11-11">
      <Name>Cohort comparison table</Name>
      <Description>Users can place two or more user cohorts side-by-side in a comparison table. Any dimension can be used as the comparison axis: time period, segment, feature adoption, plan type. Export to CSV supported.</Description>
      <PilotDriving>ENT-PC-003</PilotDriving>
      <AcceptanceCriteria>
        <Criterion>Table renders up to 10 cohorts simultaneously without performance degradation</Criterion>
        <Criterion>Columns are sortable and filterable</Criterion>
        <Criterion>Export matches the visible table state exactly</Criterion>
      </AcceptanceCriteria>
      <TestCoverage>86%</TestCoverage>
      <PilotFeedback>ENT-PC-003 Priya Shankar: gave this feature 5 stars. Cited it as the reason for 10 NPS score.</PilotFeedback>
      <RICEScore>
        <Reach>250</Reach>
        <Impact>3</Impact>
        <Confidence>88</Confidence>
        <Effort>3</Effort>
        <Total>220</Total>
      </RICEScore>
    </Feature>

  </ShippedFeatures>

  <PostLaunchBacklog>

    <Feature id="NS-F009" targetQuarter="Q1-2027" status="scoping" priority="high">
      <Name>Benchmark overlay</Name>
      <Description>Show a customer their own metrics alongside an anonymized peer cohort benchmark. Requires cross-account aggregation pipeline. Privacy-first design: no account is identifiable in the benchmark.</Description>
      <PilotDemand>Medium - 2 of 3 pilots expressed interest; ENT-PC-003 highest interest</PilotDemand>
      <EstimatedEffort>4 sprints</EstimatedEffort>
    </Feature>

    <Feature id="NS-F011" targetQuarter="Q1-2027" status="security-review" priority="high">
      <Name>Enterprise API access</Name>
      <Description>Programmatic API to query the analytics dashboard for data teams. REST endpoints for key metrics. API key authentication with scoped permissions. Rate-limited. Security review in progress.</Description>
      <PilotDemand>High - all 3 pilots requested. ENT-PC-002 put this as the number 1 future feature.</PilotDemand>
      <EstimatedEffort>6 sprints pending security review scope</EstimatedEffort>
      <BlockedBy>Security team review - 4-week backlog, review requested November 10, 2026</BlockedBy>
    </Feature>

    <Feature id="NS-F008" targetQuarter="Q1-2027" status="backlog" priority="low">
      <Name>Annotation layer</Name>
      <Description>Allow users to add annotations directly on charts (e.g., mark a deployment date, a marketing campaign, a policy change). Annotations are scoped to the dashboard or shared with the team.</Description>
      <PilotDemand>Low - 1 of 3 pilots mentioned it; no strong demand signal</PilotDemand>
      <EstimatedEffort>2 sprints</EstimatedEffort>
    </Feature>

    <Feature id="NS-F012" targetQuarter="Q2-2027" status="backlog" priority="medium">
      <Name>White-label branding</Name>
      <Description>Enterprise accounts can apply their own logo, color palette, and subdomain to the dashboard surface. Primarily an upsell feature for accounts that embed the dashboard in their own products.</Description>
      <PilotDemand>Medium - ENT-PC-003 expressed strong interest for internal reporting portal</PilotDemand>
      <EstimatedEffort>5 sprints</EstimatedEffort>
    </Feature>

  </PostLaunchBacklog>

  <SprintSummary>
    <Sprint id="S12" startDate="2026-10-02" endDate="2026-10-15" velocity="30" plannedPoints="32">
      <PlannedFeatures>NS-F001, NS-F002, NS-F005</PlannedFeatures>
      <ShippedFeatures>NS-F001, NS-F002, NS-F005</ShippedFeatures>
      <Velocity>30</Velocity>
      <Notes>Two points rolled for UI polish. All three features verified by pilot accounts within 5 days of ship.</Notes>
    </Sprint>
    <Sprint id="S13" startDate="2026-10-16" endDate="2026-10-29" velocity="28" plannedPoints="28">
      <PlannedFeatures>NS-F003, NS-F006</PlannedFeatures>
      <ShippedFeatures>NS-F003, NS-F006</ShippedFeatures>
      <Velocity>28</Velocity>
      <Notes>Performance issue on large cohort in NS-F006 caught in sprint review. James Okafor resolved on weekend before end-of-sprint demo.</Notes>
    </Sprint>
    <Sprint id="S14" startDate="2026-10-30" endDate="2026-11-11" velocity="28" plannedPoints="30">
      <PlannedFeatures>NS-F004, NS-F010, NS-F007</PlannedFeatures>
      <ShippedFeatures>NS-F004, NS-F010, NS-F007</ShippedFeatures>
      <Velocity>28</Velocity>
      <Notes>2 points UI polish on alert config UI deferred to hypercare. Messaging webhook isolated per Megan Shaw decision. All three pilot accounts signed off by November 8.</Notes>
    </Sprint>
  </SprintSummary>

</ProductBacklog>
