<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<buildJournal truck="1987 C10" color="primer gray" location="Dad's garage, Decatur AL" owner="Leah Pierce">
  <summary>
    <goal>TBI to four-barrel carburetor swap on a stock 350, then a clean first start.</goal>
    <budgetPerMonth currency="USD">100</budgetPerMonth>
    <spentToDate currency="USD">279.36</spentToDate>
  </summary>
  <sessions>
    <session date="2025-08-16" hours="4.0">
      <tasks>
        <task>Pulled the engine and set it on the stand</task>
        <task>Bagged and labeled the bell housing bolts</task>
      </tasks>
      <notes>Long day. Dad ran the hoist while I steadied it. Block looks solid.</notes>
    </session>
    <session date="2025-09-20" hours="3.5">
      <tasks>
        <task>Degreased the block and inspected for cracks</task>
        <task>Ran a compression check on the old top end</task>
      </tasks>
      <notes>No cracks. Numbers were even enough. Worth the rebuild.</notes>
    </session>
    <session date="2025-10-11" hours="3.0">
      <tasks>
        <task>Removed the old throttle body setup</task>
        <task>Scraped the intake surfaces clean</task>
      </tasks>
      <notes>Kept the old parts in a bin in case I need to go back.</notes>
    </session>
    <session date="2025-11-15" hours="4.0">
      <tasks>
        <task>Started the carburetor teardown on the bench</task>
        <task>Photographed every linkage before it came apart</task>
      </tasks>
      <notes>Laid the small parts out in a muffin tin so nothing wanders off.</notes>
    </session>
    <session date="2026-01-24" hours="3.5">
      <tasks>
        <task>Soaked the carb body, cleaned the passages</task>
        <task>Sorted primary and secondary jets, kept them paired</task>
      </tasks>
      <notes>One speck of grit ruins a jet, so I worked slow and clean.</notes>
    </session>
    <session date="2026-02-14" hours="4.0">
      <tasks>
        <task>Set the new float to the kit gauge spec</task>
        <task>Backed the idle mixture screws out about two and a half turns to start</task>
      </tasks>
      <notes>Need the bolt pattern confirmed with Jake before the gasket set order.</notes>
    </session>
  </sessions>
  <nextUp>
    <item order="1">Bench test the float level</item>
    <item order="2">Intake gasket set once the bolt pattern is confirmed</item>
    <item order="3">Low pressure fuel pump and a carb friendly line</item>
    <item order="4">Plugs and wires while the top end is open</item>
    <item order="5">Starter motor on the October garage day</item>
  </nextUp>
  <openQuestions>
    <question for="Jake">Will the stock alternator keep up once it runs again?</question>
    <question for="Jake">Reuse the old fuel line or replace the whole run?</question>
  </openQuestions>
</buildJournal>
